Jonathan Ryan Johnson

Application Development and Operations Manager

jon.johnson@ucsf.edu

(650) 516-7401

https://www.jrjohnson.dev

Ojrjohnson

Profile

Expert in team leadership, development, and psychological safety; enterprise web application development using PHP, Javascript, JSON, SQL and XML; open source contributions and community; modern web standards; cloud systems; accessible web design; automated deployment; continuous integration and system automation. Recognized for ability to adapt and expand with the growing needs of an organization and learn new skills as necessary.

Skills

Domain

Working with and Building Diverse Teams

Psychological Safety and People Management

Educational Administration and Curriculum Development

Open Source Community Maintenance and Communication

Organization Architecture and Development

Community Building

Technical

API Design and Development

Web Application Development

Accessibility

Secure Application Development and Operations

Test Driven Development
Open Source Development

Continuous Integration and Deployment

AWS and Cloud First Architecture

Talks

Jumping into Deep Work Automagic Deployment with Github Actions Microapps: A Covid-19 Case Study Cut Your Team Some Slack Handling Complicated Tasks with a Chatbot Always Be Updating Career Day at Aragon High School

Education

BA History (Pre-Law)
University of the Pacific
2003

MA Educational Administration
University of the Pacific
2005

Sample Code

PHP: Ilios Symfony Backend API Server

Javascript: Ilios EmberJS Web App I ember-cli-image-transformer I ember-noscript I ember-fontawesome

Recent Experience

Teaching and Learning Applications

Manager 2019-present While still maintaining a focus on technical leadership for the Ilios platform assumed responsibility for the Collaborative Learning Environment and the developers and support staff for CLE systems. Led the campus wide A3 effort to transform the organization and funding model for education at UCSF on behalf of the Committee for Educational Technology; facilitated internship with JCC and served as a mentor for diverse career switchers exploring technology; served as UCTech ambassador with a focus on creating an inclusive conference and recruiting first-time speakers; maintained uptime, stability, and security through multiple system upgrades; seamlessly transitioned to fully remote work; strengthened

partnerships with LTG and school technologists during the transition to pandemic remote teaching; proactively advocated for moving our team to the new Educational IT organization and managed the uncertainty and chaos of that transitional while maintaining a rigorous Ilios release schedule and on schedule upgrade of Moodle; served on the Medibiquitous Technical Advisory Group as an API and medical education standards expert.

Ilios Curriculum Management Platform

Technical Lead, Architect 2014–2019 Managed the transition from a code igniter and YUI driven application to a modern Hexagonal Symfony API with an EmberJS frontend for a user-friendly, flexible, and robust web application to collect, manage, analyze and deliver curricular information in Medical Education. Recruited for, administered, and created a code of conduct for the UCTech slack a hugely successful diverse, cross campus collaborative community for technical staff across the University of California.

Jazzee Graduate Admissions

Architect, Developer, Evangilist *2009–2014* Designed and built the Jazzee admissions system to collect and manage graduate applications and payments. Built on an XML API and a revolutionary user customizable form builder with a focus on accessibility, usability, and security. Deployed for admissions at three University of California graduate schools for admissions.